hey everyone welcome back again to
another interesting Tosca lesson today
we are going to talk about the Last
Action mode which is called wait on now
we have discussed all the remaining
action modes and in the last session I
talked about how you can use the buffer
action mode
so what is this action mode weight on
it is a way Tosca implements the dynamic
weight in its test cases
so the weight on action mode basically
interrupts the execution of your test
case until the indicated property has
the specified value which means the
condition which you have specified in
your test step should be satisfied and
then the execution will continue so it's
a dynamic mechanism of waiting not a
static mechanism and Transcendence
recommends to use this particular action
mode whenever you want to wait for any
particular condition within your
application or any particular control
which is not visible so things like that
now this wait time can be defined in the
settings called synchronization timeout
during weight on okay and to show you
that let's go to settings
okay so under settings you need to go
into t-box and on the t-box you have to
go to synchronization there you will
find the setting called synchronization
timeout during weight on so by default
uh it will be around 20 000 milliseconds
but you can either increase or decrease
this
okay so coming to the action mode weight
on and how this can be used so we are
going to pick up a placentis obstacle
okay so this is the obstacle course uh
website from test centers where you will
find different uh challenges which you
can work on and one of these obstacles
is uh you have to click on the button
calculate okay and after some time the
send button gets visible or enabled so
after that you need to click on it to
complete this obstacle
so it's basically clicking of two
buttons but the thing is the send button
is not enabled at the beginning okay so
once I click on calculate you see this
progress bar it's going to increase and
after a certain point the send button is
going to be enabled and when this will
be enabled we need to click on the send
button okay
so here you can see that it's not a
straightforward scenario right now the
send button is enabled and I can click
on it so that will complete my obstacle
but as I said it's not a pretty simple
or straightforward scenario because you
cannot directly go ahead and click on
calculate and then you can click on send
obviously one way around is you can
calculate the time it is taking to load
or to enable the send button and you can
put a static weight okay but that's not
the efficient way of doing it the most
efficient way of doing this is to put a
weight on on this particular button okay
and until this is enabled uh Tosca Will
Wait So no matter uh if this particular
bar or the time changes in the future
your test case will still run
but in the case of static weight your
test case will always wait for that
amount of time which is not at all
efficient and also it increases the
execution time in the whole uh scenario
right
so let's go ahead and work on this so
first we need to create a module and I
already have a obstacle folder so I'm
going to insert a module inside this
okay
so let's scan this application
we just need to add two controls in this
module and those are the two buttons
so we are going to select this
application and then we are going to
scan the controls
so here you can see I've got two buttons
calculate and send and I'm going to
select both of them okay
so that's all I need to do on the module
section and I'm going to close this
so that's going to create my obstacle
right and let's give it a proper name
so we will call it
33678 right
okay so that's our module and let's go
to the test cases section and here we
have got our action modes right so we
are going to create a new test case here
and we are going to call it
um the weight on
okay
wait on test
and here um we are going to pull up that
particular module which we have created
so I'm searching for obstacle 33678
and now the first step is to obviously
we just need to click on this particular
calculate button so that's our first
step
uh
and then we need to wait for this button
to be enabled right
so let's add another step here
and here we will be using the action
mode weight on okay so let's add this
again
and hit this time around I am going to
use the action mode weight on okay
and you will see uh the weight on action
mode has got a different color it's
yellow in the background okay
also we need to put a condition here
because the weight on depends on the
condition being satisfied for the
particular control okay so what we are
going to do is we are going to say
um enabled equals to
true
okay so since it is disabled now when it
when this particular button is enabled
the weight on will be satisfied and the
execution will continue okay
uh let's go ahead and first change just
the steps so I will say click calculate
and then
wait for send enable
okay and then we'll add our final step
to click on it okay so let's go ahead
and do that as well
and here finally I am going to click on
that particular button right
so I will say click Send
so this is
um the whole test case you can see
so there are basically three steps first
we click on calculate then we use the
weight on to wait for that button to be
enabled and then we go ahead and click
on it okay let's go ahead and execute
this in scratch book and let's see if it
works
so it clicks on the calculate button and
as you can see it is going to wait until
this progress bar completes or the send
button is basically enabled that's the
condition we have put so it's going to
wait until that
and then once it's enabled it's going to
click on it okay
so it's a pretty simple obstacle or a
scenario once you know how to use weight
on but whenever or for whichever
scenario you have to put some
synchronization or you have to wait for
some particular controls on the page
uh no matter what just try to use this
particular uh weight on mechanism or
some other Dynamic mechanism available
in Tosca rather than using uh the t-box
weight which is a static bit so whatever
time you provide in that weight it will
wait for that time no matter even if
your control is already available so
which is not an efficient way of doing
it and also it's not a best practice
so keep this in mind when you are
automating your scenarios in Tosca and
try to use the weight on action mode
um whenever you are working with
synchronization or timeout issues
so that's all for this particular
session uh in the next session we'll be
continuing with some more interesting
features of Tosca